{"tossups": [{"question": ". In of this painter's works, the Ten Commandments descend from a red patch of sky in the upper left and a serpent wraps round a T-shaped wooden post. The center of that painting by this artist is dominated by a tree that is dying on its left side and has lush foliage on its right. In another of his paintings, a boy in red stockings plays with an infant on the left, while a girl in white holding a rosary kneels on the right on one of this artist's namesake carpets. Burgomaster Meyer stands to the left of a navy blue-clad Virgin Mary in that painting by this artist of An Allegory of the Old and New Testaments. In the most famous painting of this artist of the Darmstadt Madonna, an open book, a globe, and a lute stand rest between the title figures, above an anamorphic skull. For 10 points, name this German Renaissance painter of The Ambassadors. ", "answer": "Hans Holbein the Younger", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": " One character in this work asks another whether his favorite authors are Baudelaire and Stephen King. One character in this work tells the story of his adulterous mother and his father who was run over by a bus, after being asked why he keeps two picture frames that are empty. Another character in this works has two girls, two cats, and two parakeets, but no sons. One character in this work complains about his black drag-queen apartment-mate who wears a kimono and plucks his eyebrows all day, and about his landlady's savage dog, whom he feeds poisoned hamburger meat. That character in this play pushes another off a bench before starting a fight, in which he impales himself on a knife. For 10 points, name this Edward Albee play in which Jerry accosts Peter in Central Park after a visit to the title location. ", "answer": "Zoo Story ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "These objects cannot form in the absence of CCNs, some of which are believed to be produced by phytoplankton. The necessary conditions for the formation of these objects are described by a law which combines Raoult's law and the Kelvin curvature effect, known as the Kohler equation. Cold ones may grow by riming, leading to the formation of graupel. They begin to form when enough nuclei are activated by achieving ambient saturation sufficient to pass the critical peak. When these objects are electrified, forming a main charging zone at intermediate altitude, they may discharge via a process that forms a stepped leader and is followed by J streamers. Nacreous ones are a rare stratospheric example of these, which are believed to facilitate ozone depletion. For 10 points, name these agglomerations of droplets and crystals which come in noctilucent and cumulus varieties.", "answer": "cloud", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Ethel Merman's cameo role in this film as Lieutenant Hurwitz was her last film appearance. One character in this film accidentally rips out another character's IV drip with her guitar while singing \"River of Jordan\". One character in this film asks Joey whether he's ever been in a Turkish prison before. An old white lady in this film translates jive for two African-American men who can't communicate with other white people. In this film, McCroskey declares that he picked the wrong week to stop sniffing glue, Roger Murdock denies that he is really Kareem Abdul-Jabbar, and Dr. Rumack repeatedly tells various characters not to call him \"Shirley\". For 10 points, rampant food poisoning necessitates Ted Striker taking over as pilot in what 1980 Zucker, Abrahams, and Zucker spoof film that revived the careers of Robert Stack, Lloyd Bridges, and Leslie Nielsen? ", "answer": "Airplane! ", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "The Capehart Act was a federal intervention into the market for these entities. Catherine Bower led a movement named for these entities, which succeeded in passing the Wagner-Steagall act.  One variant of these entities in the late-19th century Midwest were called \"soddies.\" The purchase of one of these entities in Missouri triggered a ruling that judicial enforcement is a state action under the Fourteenth Amendment. That 1948 case, Shelley v. Kraemer, ended the racist practice of restrictive covenants on these things. The GI Bill introduced VA Loans to help soldiers obtain these things, and an early criticism of Levittown was the homogeneity of these in that suburb. For 10 points, name these quintessentially American properties which were negatively affected by the subprime mortgage crisis.", "answer": "houses [or homes, or housing units; prompt \"buildings\"]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This man was the first Master Mahan according to the Pearl of Great Price, in which he takes that title after entering a covenant with Satan. In the Qur'an, a raven is sent to help teach this man by Allah, as told in the fifth Sura, \"The Table.\" Heber, Jael's husband in the Book of Judges, belongs to a tribe whose name means \"sons of [this man]\", who preacher William Branham alleged to have an inhuman father with his two-seedline theory. Methusael's son Lamech is a sixth-generation descendant of this man who, if any harm comes to him, is avenged seventy-sevenfold. After this man's most notable action, Seth was born and this man exiled himself to the land of Nod. That act by this farmer was a reaction to a well-received sheep sacrifice, and led God to \"mark\" him. For 10 points, name this early Biblical man, a son of Adam who asked \"Am I my brother's keeper?\" after killing Abel.", "answer": "Cain [or Qayin; do not accept \"Herman Cain\"]", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "One polity of this name paid 300,000 florins to subsume the lands of Arnold of Egmont, Duke of Guelders, and absorbed that land after Arnold's death. A female leader of this place undid many of its powers by signing the Great Privilege. It took its name from a post-Roman tribe led by Godomar and the law-code creator Gundobad. A party of this name which fought against the Armagnacs in the 1400s was led by John the Fearless. One duke of this place was count of Charolais while he appointed his brother to figurehead the League of the Public Weal. It was dissolved after its leader was killed in the snow at Nancy. That leader, Charles the Bold, lost out to France's Spider-King Louis XI, ending a Duchy of this name which also included the modern Netherlands. For 10 points, give this name for a historical region of Europe which now takes up southeastern France and produces wines.", "answer": "Burgundy [or Bourgogne, or Burgundians]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This composer wrote a suite  whose \"Prologue\" movement opens with two solo trumpets over a drumroll. That piece also includes \"Dance\" and \"Burlesque\" movements and is called Music for the Theatre. He dedicated his twelve-tone Piano Fantasy to the memory of William Kappel, He wrote a composition for trumpet, English horn, and string orchestra, which was based on incidental music he had written for Irwin Shaw's play Quiet City. Another composition quotes folk songs like \"El Palo Verde,\" and one of his ballets ends when the title character is shot by Pat Garrett. He also composed a ballet score that features variations on the Shaker melody \"Simple Gifts,\" commissioned by Martha Graham. For 10 points, name this American composer of El Sal\u00c3\u00b3n M\u00c3\u00a9xico, Billy the Kid, and Appalachian Spring.", "answer": "Aaron Copland ", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "In a multi-particle system, multiple orthonormal forms of this quantity are multiplied to compute the Hartree product. For a particle described by the Klein-Gordon equation, this quantity's d'Alembertian is equal to negative m squared c squared divided by h-bar squared times, this quantity. This quantity is antisymmetric under fermion interchange. The Hamiltonian operator on this function is proportional to this function's time derivative. Non-square-integrable examples of this function are non-normalizable and thus non-physical. The square of the magnitude of this function represents a probability density for the location of the particles it describes. For 10 points, name this function which is the solution of the Schrodinger equation and which describes the state of a quantum particle.", "answer": "wavefunction", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Toward the end of this novel, one elderly character strangles another character to death in a fit of madness, having earlier attempted to strangle the same girl. Another character's former mistress, Annouchka, was hanged because of his attempt to assassinate the Czar. One character in this novel is mutilated after slipping from his roof; that is the greedy shopkeeper Maigrat. The protagonist hides the body of a guard murdered by a young street urchin, Jeanlin, and this novel also features a character whose nickname comes from his many brushes with death, Bonnemort. The anarchist Souvarine causes a flood before leaving Montsou, and the protagonist kills his rival Chaval in duel, after which the protagonist's lover dies of suffocation underground. For 10 points, name this novel in which Catherine Maheu and \u00c3\u2030tienne Lantier take part in a coalminers' strike, written by Emile Zola.", "answer": "Germinal", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This man was infuriated when his uncle, William the Duke of Oldenburg, had his territory annexed, and hired the Scotsman Michael Barclay de Tolly for his army. During his rule, he lost one battle when he took the abandoned Pratzen Heights and despite sending in his reserves, and through the treaty of Friedrikshamm his country formally annexed Finland.  He was the first ruler to hire the reform-minded advisor Mikhail Speransky, who established the State Council to advise him, and he was the second ruler to hire artillery general Aleksey Arakcheyev. He withdrew his nation's ships from a blockade called Continental System, breaking with an agreement signed after his army at Friedland, for which he boarded a barge to sign the treaty of Tilsit. For 10 points, name this successor of Paul I, a tsar whose army fought at Borodino against Napoleon.", "answer": "Alexander I Romanov ", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One of these creatures is always depicted opposite the bearded Gaulish god Smertrios, such as on the Pillar of the Boatmen. An Oceanian goddess who takes this creature's form is often called Julunggul or Yulunggul. The brain-eating heads of two of these creatures grow from the shoulders of a tyrant opposed by the smith Kaveh and by Fereydun in the Shahnameh; that ruler is Zahhak. When two of these creatures caressed the ears of Melampus, he gained the ability to understand animal speech. Eurydice was killed by one of these creatures, which made up the lower body of Cecrops. A mating pair of them was struck by the walking-stick of Tiresias, leading Hera to blind him. For 10 points, name this creature which is featured in the circular Ouroboros symbol biting its own legless tail.", "answer": "snakes [or serpents]", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "One poem in this collection asks why the bull and boar \"so sillily / Dissemble weakness\" given that they \"might swallow and feed upon\" men. That poem begins \"Why are we by all creatures waited on?\" Its author writes that \"a holy thirsty dropsy melts me yet\" in a poem from this collection on the death of his wife, \"Since she whom I loved hath paid her last debt.\" Another poem in this collection concludes that \"I, / Except you enthrall me, never shall be free, / Nor ever chaste, except you ravish me.\" That poem asks its addressee to \"break, blow, burn, and make me new.\" Its best-known poem asserts that \"one short sleep past, we wake eternally,\" and this collection also includes a poem beginning \"Batter my heart, three-person'd God.\"  For 10 points, name this set of nineteen religious poems, including one that begins \"Death be not proud,\" written by John Donne.", "answer": "Holy Sonnets [or Divine Meditations]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The subtitle of Dean MacCannell's The Tourist alludes to the title of this earlier work, one section of which states that the dolicho-blond European man is more easily able to revert to barbarism. It argues that selective surveillance of a law regarding waste leads to the creation of accredited canons of a central concept. It argues that the title group sees no need to question the \"instinctive revulsion\" that all men have against change. The author of this work identifies two forms of the title concept of another chapter, the first of which is merely an \"inarticulate or inchoate animism\" that is observable both in \"the barbarian of the predatory culture\" and in the modern \"sporting man.\" That chapter, which analyzes the \"gambling propensity,\" is \"The Belief in Luck.\" This work argues that \"invidious comparison\" inspires acts of \"pecuniary emulation.\" Introducing the concept of conspicuous consumption, for 10 points, name this \"economic study of institutions\" by Thorstein Veblen.", "answer": "The Theory of the Leisure Class ", "category": "Social Science"}, {"question": "A 50th Anniversary re-issue of this album included such extra tracks as \"Stella by Starlight\" and \"Love for Sale\". One track on this album replaces the last chord of a twelve-bar blues progression with the dominant seventh of the flattened leading tone, the only track on which Wynton Kelly is featured as pianist. The improvisations on this album were based on the theories of George Russell. One track on this album alternates between D Dorian and E-flat Dorian. \"Blue in Green\" is the only track on this album not to feature Cannonball Adderley. Pianist Bill Evans claims credit for the introduction to its final track, \"Flamenco Sketches\". For 10 points, \"So What\" and \"Freddie Freeloader\" are tracks on what pioneering album in modal jazz by Miles Davis, the best-selling album of all time?", "answer": "Kind of Blue ", "category": "Trash"}, {"question": "Alkoxy examples of these are produced by thermal decomposition of dialkyl peroxides. N-bromosuccinimide serves as a donor of these compounds, which are also intermediates in the degradation of nitrites to nitrosoalcohols in the Barton reaction. Gomberg's reagent was the first persistent one prepared, and was relatively unreactive due to steric hindrance from three phenyl groups. All the intermediates, but none of the products of the Birch reduction are this type of compound. Hyperfine interactions in these substances can be measured by means of ESR, in which they resonate when radiated with gigahertz-frequency photons. Photodissociation of CFCs yields substances of this type which are believed to be primarily responsible for the depletion of the ozone layer. For 10 points, name these typically-reactive substances which contain unpaired electrons.", "answer": "free radicals", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "In this work's final chapter, its author proposes to refute the opposing views of both Pierre Bayle and William Warburton on the relationship between religion and politics. Another section of this work argues that there should be no \"partial society within the State\" and that citizens should have no communication with each other when voting. It argues that sovereignty is inalienable, and its author contrasts one of its central concepts with the \"will of all,\" which is the sum of all private interests. Its author defines its title concept as a submission to the \"direction of the general will.\"  For 10 points, name this work of political philosophy that begins, \"Man is born free, and everywhere he is in chains,\" written by Jean-Jacques Rousseau.", "answer": "Of the Social Contract, or Principles of Political Right [or Du contrat social, ou principes du droit politique]", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "The Mx1 protein in macrophages appears to specifically exist to respond to this pathogen. The B form of this pathogen lacks an M2 proton channel, making that form immune to amantadine. This virus can undergo reassortment since it contains multiple distinct negative-sense RNA segments which can be exchanged when multiple strains of it coexist in a given cell. One surface glycoprotein found on these orthomyxoviruses cleaves sialic acids from newly-synthesized virions, enabling their escape from the cell. That protein, which is inhibited by drugs like oseltamivir, has nine known forms and is neuraminidase. This virus's hemagglutinin protein can only be cleaved by proteases in the respiratory tract. For 10 points, name this virus whose H1N1 form caused a pandemic in 1918.", "answer": " influenzavirus", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "In one story by an author from this country, the title character spends every Sunday afternoon at the Jardins Publiques people-watching and eavesdropping until she overhears a young couple making fun of her fur wrap. In another story from here, Miss Jose sings \"This Life is Weary\" on the piano. In another story from this country, Pearl Fulton inspires the title emotion in Bertha Young under a pear tree. In one story from this country, Laura brings leftover sandwiches from the title event to the house of Scott, who was killed in a riding accident. Besides the author of \"Miss Brill\" and \"Bliss\", another author from this country wrote of Kerewin adoptive relationship with the mute Simon. For 10 points, name this country of origin of the author of \"The Garden Party\", Katherine Mansfield, and of Keri Hulme, whose novel The Bone People deals with the Maori.", "answer": "New Zealand", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "During this conflict, the Sheriff Essex revealed plans to attack London by setting roosters' feet on fire and setting them loose. One commander in this conflict was captured after taking shelter in a windmill outside of St. Pancras Priory. That commander, Richard of Cornwall, lost the same battle which saw a defeat for the Prince at Sussex Downs. The peace that ended this conflict re-affirmed the Charter of the Forest and was supplemented in the Statute of Marlborough. This conflict, which contains the Battle of Lewes and was ended after the Siege of Kenilworth, was started by the ruling monarch's refusal to honor the Provisions of Oxford, and the aggressors in this conflict were lead by Simon de Montfort. For 10 points, name this 1264-1267 conflict, in which a certain group of nobleman rebelled against the rule of Henry III. ", "answer": "Second Baron", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}], "bonuses": []}